your smartphone has a variety of components
您的智能手机有多种组件
that can do dozens of different things
可以做几十种不同的事情
and the brain
和大脑
at the center of all these components and functions
在所有这些组件和功能的中心
is the system on a chip
是芯片上的系统吗？
or Soc for short
或简称Soc
when you watch a video such as this one
当你看这样的视频时
phone a friend across the country
给全国各地的朋友打电话
or navigate through a city using GPS
或使用GPS在城市中导航
it may seem like magic or alien tech
它可能看起来像魔法或外星科技
but in reality
但实际上
these feats of technology are all performed
这些技术的壮举都是通过
inside this Soc
在这个Soc里面
which is designed and manufactured
它是设计和制造的
through the hard work of countless scientists
通过无数科学家的辛勤工作
and engineers
和工程师
in this episode
在这一集里
we're going to explore each section of this Soc
我们将探索这个Soc的每个部分
and then piece together the processes
然后拼凑这些过程
this system on a chip goes through
这个芯片上的系统通过
when you do something as routine
当你例行公事地做某事时
as snap a photo and post it online
拍张照片并发布到网上
these chips are unfathomably complex
这些芯片极其复杂
as there are between 5 and 10 billion transistors
因为有5到100亿晶体管
that make up the Soc
组成Soc
and they all need to fit into an area
它们都需要适应一个区域
the size of a penny
一便士大小
this is a complex topic
这是一个复杂的话题
and there are many avenues that we could explore
我们可以探索许多途径
but in order not to overload your brain with details
但为了不让你的大脑因细节而超负荷
we've decided to focus on the following aspects
我们决定专注于以下方面
first we'll start with a few notes and caveats
首先，我们将从一些注释和警告开始
and then we'll dive into the layout
然后我们将深入布局
and key sections of the system on a chip
和芯片系统的关键部分
next we'll explore how data flows through the Soc
接下来我们将探讨数据如何流经Soc
using the example of
使用的例子
what happens when you take a picture
当你拍照时会发生什么？
then we'll look at some of the complexity inside
然后我们来看看其中的复杂性
the central processing unit or
中央处理器或者
CPU block of the Soc
Soc的CPU块
and stick around until the end
并坚持到最后
where we'll discuss how scientists
我们将讨论科学家如何
and engineers design and manufacture these microchips
工程师设计和制造这些微芯片
and we'll explore
我们将探索
what a nanoscopic view of the Soc
Soc的纳米视图
would actually look like
实际上看起来像
compared to this visualization
与这个可视化相比
so for this video grab a snack
所以在这个视频中，吃点零食。
sit down and maybe take some notes if you feel like it
如果你愿意可以坐下来记笔记
because this is going to be one
因为这将是一个
very thorough and incredibly detailed video
非常彻底和非常详细的视频
to start this video is sponsored by Gerber Labs
这个视频是由格柏实验室赞助的
a quick reliable
快速可靠
and user friendly provider of printed circuit boards
和用户友好的印刷电路板供应商
next
下一个
this microchip is actually composed of two key parts
这个微芯片实际上由两个关键部分组成
on top is the DRAM
上面是DRAM
or the dynamic Random Access memory
或动态随机存取存储器
which is the working memory of your smartphone
这是您智能手机的工作内存
and on the bottom is the Soc the
底部是Soc
brains of your smartphone
智能手机的大脑
FYI the long term memory where all your music
仅供参考你所有音乐的长期记忆
apps files and the operating system are saved
应用程序文件和操作系统被保存
is over here in the flash storage
在闪存里
we have a separate episode on that microchip
我们在那个芯片上有单独的插曲
and you can find it here
你可以在这里找到它
but in this episode we're going to focus on the Soc
但是在这一集里，我们将关注Soc
this setup is called a package on package microchip
这种设置称为封装微芯片上的封装
or pop technically this is the microchip
或者从技术上讲，这是微芯片
and the separate layers of the DRAM and Soc
以及DRAM和Soc的单独层
are each called a die
每个都被称为模具
however
然而
the word chip has evolved to mean a variety of things
芯片这个词已经演变成意味着各种各样的东西
so while all of these rectangular components are
所以当所有这些矩形组件
microchips or chips
微芯片或芯片
both the DRAM and system on a chip
DRAM和片上系统
are also called chips
也被称为芯片
even though they're just half of the overall package
即使它们只是整个包裹的一半
on package microchip
封装微芯片
moving on we may make comparisons
继续前进，我们可以进行比较
or analogies between smartphones and humans
或者智能手机和人类之间的类比
for example we call the Soc the brain
例如，我们称Soc为大脑
or the camera can be considered similar to a human eye
或者相机可以被认为类似于人眼
however these are two very very different systems
然而，这是两个非常非常不同的系统
and while the analogies may be useful conceptual tools
虽然类比可能是有用的概念工具
the underlying principles behind Socs in human brains
人类大脑中SOC背后的基本原理
and how they work
以及它们是如何工作的
are entirely different
完全不同
finally the companies that design these Socs
最后，设计这些SOC的公司
are incredibly secretive
非常隐秘
about the specifics of how they work
关于它们如何工作的细节
and what the actual designs look like
以及实际设计是什么样子的
it takes dozens of different companies to design
需要数十家不同的公司来设计
the optimal layout
最优布局
for billions of transistors
数十亿晶体管
to perfectly execute the functions of a phone
完美执行手机功能
and a separate set of companies
和一组单独的公司
to manufacture the billions of chips
制造数十亿芯片
used by all our phones
被我们所有的手机使用
so in this video
所以在这个视频中
we'll provide you with the best information we can
我们会向你提供最好的信息
considering the company's secrecy
考虑到公司的保密性
of intellectual property
知识产权
as a result
结果
this information will be mixed and woven together
这些信息将被混合和编织在一起
from different sources
来自不同的来源
for example this is an LG V10 smartphone from 2015
例如，这是2015年的LG V10智能手机
and it uses a Qualcomm Snapdragon 808
而且用的是高通骁龙808
but
但是
due to the limited availability of information on it
由于关于它的信息有限
we'll have to use
我们得用
images and information from the Apple A12
来自Apple A12的图像和信息
and A13 microchip
和A13微芯片
in the iPhone 10 and iPhone 11
在10iPhone和11iPhone
as well as the Qualcomm Snapdragon 865
还有高通骁龙865
in the Samsung S20
在三星S20中
all of these microchips have different performance
所有这些微芯片都有不同的性能
metrics and different capabilities
指标和不同的能力
but fundamentally they work on similar principles
但基本上他们的工作原理相似
okay with all of these notes covered
好吧，覆盖了所有这些笔记
let's move on to understand how this system on a chip
让我们继续了解这个芯片上的系统是如何
works
作品
a human brain has different sections
人脑有不同的部分
for processing information
用于处理信息
received by your eyes and ears
你的眼睛和耳朵收到了
a different section for speech
不同的演讲部分
ones for controlling your taste smell
用来控制你的味觉气味的
movement balance involuntary functions and so on
运动平衡无意识功能等等
rather similarly
相当相似
this system on a chip
这个芯片上的系统
is divided into different functional areas
分为不同的功能区域
here's a graphical representation
这是一个图形表示
called a block diagram
称为框图
the key areas in the Soc the
Soc中的关键领域
CPU containing multiple cores
包含多个内核的CPU
the GPU which renders graphics
渲染图形的GPU
the shared memory cache which is usually around 4 to
共享内存缓存通常约为4到
8 megabytes the digital signal processor which
8兆字节的数字信号处理器
interfaces with things like the speakers
与扬声器之类的东西的接口
microphones sensors and many other things
麦克风传感器和许多其他东西
the display engine
显示引擎
which communicates with the touchscreen display
它与触摸屏显示器通信
the video processor
视频处理器
which compresses and decompresses images and video
压缩和解压缩图像和视频
and enables 4K video recording and playback
并能4K录像和回放
the image signal processor
图像信号处理器
which processes pictures and video
处理图片和视频
taken by the cameras
被摄像机拍下
the modem
调制解调器
which interfaces with the various wireless networks
与各种无线网络接口
the storage controller
存储控制器
which saves and loads information from the flash
它从闪存中保存和加载信息
storage microchip
存储微芯片
the memory controller
内存控制器
which connects to the DRAM microchip
它连接到DRAM微芯片
located on top of this one
位于这个顶部
the security enclave which executes encryption
执行加密的安全飞地
and manages the public and private keys
并管理公钥和私钥
a number of peripheral functions such as clocks
许多外围功能，例如时钟
temperature sensors
温度传感器
debug ports and general purpose inputs and outputs
调试端口和通用输入和输出
an always on microcontroller unit and finally
一个永远在线的微控制器单元，最后
the network on chip or Nock
片上网络或Nock
which arbitrates or manages data flow through the Soc
仲裁或管理通过Soc的数据流
the DRAM and other parts of the phone
DRAM和手机的其他部分
furthermore some Socs may have on board
此外，一些Socs可能在船上
power management circuits
电源管理电路
that complement the power management
补充电源管理
performed by separate chips
由单独的芯片执行
outside the Soc
Soc之外
additionally some Socs such as apples
另外还有一些袜子，比如苹果。
have a neural processing unit or an NPU
有一个神经处理单元或一个NPU
that is specialized circuitry
那是专门的电路
that can execute machine learning algorithms
可以执行机器学习算法
far more efficiently
更有效
than the CPU
比CPU
both in terms of speed and more importantly
无论是速度还是更重要的
power consumption
耗电量
one confusing detail
一个令人困惑的细节
is that different generations of Socs
不同代的Socs
use different marketing names
使用不同的营销名称
and mix multiple functions into different functional
并将多种功能混合成不同的功能
blocks for example
例如块
here's the block diagram of the Snapdragon 808
这是骁龙808的框图
versus the diagram for the Snapdragon 865
与骁龙865的图表对比
and here's the block diagram for Apple's A12 chip
这是苹果A12芯片的框图
each company's marketing team
每个公司的营销团队
may decide to provide differing
可能决定提供不同的
block diagrams
框图
to try to impress the consumers
试图给消费者留下深刻印象
which at times can certainly be confusing
这有时肯定会令人困惑
let's move on
让我们继续前进
and explore a real life example
并探索一个现实生活中的例子
of how data moves around your smartphone
数据如何在您的智能手机中移动
when you take a picture
当你拍照的时候
but before that one quick note
但在那之前，一个简短的说明
if you enjoy watching this video
如果你喜欢看这个视频
or if you think it's a useful learning tool
或者如果你认为这是一个有用的学习工具
make sure to like
确保喜欢
and comment on this video
并评论此视频
as well as share it with others
以及与他人分享
with your help we can get this video to over
在你的帮助下，我们可以完成这个视频
10,000 comments and more than 100,000 likes
10,000条评论和超过100,000个赞
but for now let's get back to understanding
但现在让我们回到理解
what happens
会发生什么
when you take a picture on your smartphone
当你在智能手机上拍照时
first
第一
the photons from the scene enter the camera's lenses
场景中的光子进入相机的镜头
flow through a color filter array
流过滤色器阵列
and hit the sensor's photo diode pixels
并击中传感器的光电二极管像素
these color filtered photons
这些滤色光子
are then absorbed by each photodiode
然后被每个光电二极管吸收
and converted into an analog electrical current
并转换成模拟电流
which is then converted into a digital
然后将其转换为数字
12 bit binary value
12位二进制值
a 12 megapixel cameras image has
一个1200万像素的摄像头图像有
12 million of these 12 bit binary values
1200万12位二进制值
note that each pixel is either red or green or blue
请注意，每个像素要么是红色、绿色或蓝色
and thus the overall image is considered raw
因此整体图像被认为是原始的
and still
而且仍然
has to undergo a number of image processing steps
必须经历许多图像处理步骤
to turn it from a raw image
将其从原始图像转换为原始图像
into a recognizable picture where the pixels
变成一张可识别的图片，其中像素
each have a red and green and blue value
每个都有一个红色、绿色和蓝色的值
but before these processes take place
但是在这些过程发生之前
this image data must be stored somewhere
这些图像数据必须存储在某个地方
and as a result
结果是
it's sent to the smartphone's working memory
它被发送到智能手机的工作内存中
or DRAM to do this
或DRAM来做到这一点
the data travels from the camera and enters the Soc
数据从相机传输并进入Soc
through a mobile industry processor interface or MPI
通过移动工业处理器接口或MPI
which can send or receive data
可以发送或接收数据
at around 5 to 8 gigabits per second
大约每秒5到8千兆位
this image data is then routed by the network on chip
然后，该图像数据由片上网络路由
arbitrator through the Soc
仲裁员通过Soc
to the memory controller and into the DRAM
到内存控制器并进入DRAM
which as mentioned before
如前所述
is located on the die above the Soc
位于Soc上方的模具上
there are two quick things to note
有两件事要注意
first the data path between the Soc and the DRAM
首先是Soc和DRAM之间的数据通路
is shared by everything
被万物共享
in this scenario
在这种情况下
it's the job of the network arbitrator
这是网络仲裁员的工作
to prioritize the incoming sensor data
优先考虑传入的传感器数据
of the uncompressed raw image
未压缩的原始图像
so that no data from the camera is lost
这样就不会丢失相机中的数据
and thus
因此
the arbitrator streams the raw image directly into the
仲裁员将原始图像直接流式传输到
DRAM second
DRAM秒
a 12 megapixel
1200万像素
uncompressed raw image takes up around 24 megabytes
未压缩的原始图像占用大约24兆字节
however the memory cache on the Soc is typically
但是Soc上的内存缓存通常是
4 to 8 megabytes
4到8兆字节
and is shared among all the processes on the Soc
并在Soc上的所有进程之间共享
therefore when the image signal processor
因此当图像信号处理器
or the video processor
或视频处理器
works on a recently taken picture
适用于最近拍摄的照片
in order to make it viewable or to compress it
为了使其可见或压缩它
they can
他们可以
only work on small subsections of the overall image
仅适用于整体图像的小部分
leaving the entire image temporarily stored on the DRAM
将整个图像临时存储在DRAM上
this also happens while watching a video
看视频时也会发生这种情况
playing a video game or using pretty much any app
玩电子游戏或使用几乎任何应用程序
okay let's get back to the raw
好吧，让我们回到原始
image data of the picture that was taken by the camera
相机拍摄的图片的图像数据
and then sent to the MIPPI
然后发送到MIPPI
routed through the Soc and stored in the DRAM
通过Soc路由并存储在DRAM中
the next step is for the image signal processor
下一步是图像信号处理器
or ISP on the Soc
或Soc上的ISP
to read the raw uncompressed image data
读取原始未压缩图像数据
and perform a number of image processing steps
并执行许多图像处理步骤
these steps involve first
这些步骤首先涉及
correcting for darker pixels on the edge of the sensor
校正传感器边缘的较暗像素
due to lens shading
由于镜头阴影
then the ISP performs the demosaicing process
然后ISP执行去马赛克过程
which involves taking the image data
其中涉及获取图像数据
and the pattern on the camera's color filter
以及相机滤色器上的图案
and calculating a red
并计算红色
green and blue value for every pixel
每个像素的绿色和蓝色值
next the image signal processor denoises sharpens
接下来图像信号处理器去噪锐化
enhances the image and color corrects it
增强图像和颜色校正它
because the red green and blue filters on the camera
因为相机上的红绿蓝滤镜
don't directly match the hue of the red
不要直接匹配红色的色调
green and blue pixels in the display
显示屏中的绿色和蓝色像素
and finally
最后
the image signal processor tone maps the image
图像信号处理器色调映射图像
after all this we have a picture with 12 million pixels
经过这一切我们有一张1200万像素的图片
each with an 8 bit red green and blue value
每个都有一个8位的红绿和蓝色值
to get the picture to promptly appear on your screen
让图片立即出现在您的屏幕上
another series of steps are involved
涉及到另一系列步骤
the RGB image data
RGB图像数据
is taken from the image signal processor
取自图像信号处理器
sent to the GPU
发送到GPU
where it gets overlaid into the graphics of the camera
它被叠加到相机的图形中
app and scale to fit the screen
应用程序和缩放以适应屏幕
the resulting RGB values
生成的RGB值
get sent to the display processor
发送到显示处理器
and then the image is routed to the display
然后图像被路由到显示器
where it's converted into intensities of current
转化为电流强度
in order to light up the corresponding pattern of red
为了点亮相应的红色图案
green and blue pixels
绿色和蓝色像素
and there you go
给你。
a picture taken by the camera and whoosh
相机拍的照片嗖的一声
displayed on the screen
显示在屏幕上
but we're not done yet
但我们还没完
how is the picture saved on your smartphone
图片是如何保存在智能手机上的？
well first the picture needs to be compressed
首先，图片需要压缩
and to do that
为了做到这一点
the uncompressed image currently residing in DRAM
当前驻留在DRAM中的未压缩图像
is sent to a dedicated video coding processor
被发送到专用的视频编码处理器
where it first gets converted from red
它第一次从红色转换的地方
green and blue values
绿色和蓝色值
into YUV or luminance
进入YUV或亮度
blue chrominance and red chrominance values
蓝色色度和红色色度值
next this data undergoes a series of algorithms
接下来，这些数据经过一系列算法
in order to remove information
为了删除信息
that is undetectable to the human eye
人眼无法察觉的
and compresses the image
并压缩图像
into approximately a 3 megabyte
变成大约3兆字节
JPEG format
JPEG格式
this compressed image is sent back to the DRAM
此压缩图像被发送回DRAM
and then routed to the smartphone's flash memory
然后路由到智能手机的闪存
for long term storage
用于长期存储
now if you were to send this picture to a friend
现在如果你把这张照片发给朋友
the compressed image
压缩图像
would get brought back into the DRAM
会被带回DRAM
and then routed to the modem
然后路由到调制解调器
where it's divided and assembled into packets
在那里它被分成并组装成数据包
then sent to the
然后发送到
4G 5g or Wi-Fi microchip
4G 5g或Wi-Fi微芯片
converted into electromagnetic waves
转换成电磁波
and sent to a cellular or Wi Fi network
并发送到蜂窝或无线网络
one thing we've talked a lot about
有一件事我们谈了很多
is the movement of data
是数据的移动
through the Soc
通过Soc
all of this data movement between the blocks
所有这些数据在块之间的移动
runs over connecting wires
绕过连接线
and what is part of the network
什么是网络的一部分
on a chip this network has routers and switches
这个网络在芯片上有路由器和交换机
for shared access to routes and targets like the DRAM
用于共享对DRAM等路由和目标的访问
the routers and switches arbitrate the flow of data
路由器和交换机仲裁数据流
and act like digital traffic lights
就像数字交通灯一样
and the pathways act as a digital highway
这些路径就像一条数字高速公路
these highways have different widths of wires
这些高速公路有不同宽度的电线
based on what they're talking to
根据他们的谈话内容
and the amount of information that needs to be sent
以及需要发送的信息量
depending on required data rates
取决于所需的数据速率
there are typically 128 or
通常有128或
256 wires running parallel to one another
256根线彼此平行
carrying one bit at a time
一次携带一个位
and operating between 500 and 1500 megahertz
工作频率在500到1500兆赫之间
in order to avoid wasting power
为了避免浪费电力
from your smartphone's battery
来自智能手机的电池
the frequency
频率
in resulting data transfer rates across the network
网络数据搬迁率
on a chip ramp up and down
在芯片斜坡上上下
depending on the requirements of the applications
根据申请的要求
you're running
你在跑
and this feature is called dynamic frequency scaling
这个特性称为动态频率缩放
before we explore the CPU
在我们探索CPU之前
and see how these chips are designed
看看这些芯片是如何设计的
and manufactured
和制造
let's take a quick break
让我们休息一下
and talk about this video's sponsor
谈谈这个视频的赞助商
Gerber Labs every Soc
格柏实验室每个Soc
eventually makes its way onto a printed circuit board
最终进入印刷电路板
along with other components
与其他组件一起
that are put together
放在一起
to create a vast array of different circuits
创造出大量不同的电路
you can start your own creative circuits
你可以开始自己的创作循环
by building a printed circuit board
通过建造印刷电路板
from Gerber Labs
来自Gerber Labs
Gerber Labs is founded by electrical engineers
格柏实验室由电气工程师创立
for electrical engineers
对于电气工程师
they make it easy to get boards with consistent quality
它们使获得质量一致的电路板变得容易
quick turnaround and reliable shipping
快速周转和可靠的运输
check them out with the link in the description
使用描述中的链接查看它们
and stick to the end of this video
并坚持到这段视频的结尾
to receive a discount code for your order
接收您订单的折扣码
okay
好吧
so thus far
到目前为止
we've glossed over
我们掩盖了
the functionality of each of these blocks
这些块中的每一个的功能
in the Soc but now
在Soc但现在
let's quickly take a look
我们赶紧来看看
into the central processing unit
进入中央处理器
or CPU section of the Soc
或Soc的CPU部分
as you see there are multiple cores
如您所见，有多个核心
and each core can run part of a program
每个内核都可以运行程序的一部分
by executing instructions
通过执行指令
if we focus on just one of these cores
如果我们只关注其中一个核心
we can see that inside it
我们可以在里面看到
there is another incredibly complex set of blocks
还有另一组极其复杂的积木
that depict the different functional sections
描绘了不同的功能部分
and the data flow between them
以及它们之间的数据流
there is a ton of information in this block diagram
这个框图里有很多信息
and we're planning on making an entire series
我们计划制作一整个系列
to explain it all
来解释这一切
but for now here are the CPU's memory caches
但现在这里是CPU的内存缓存
the instructions such as add multiply load store
添加乘法加载存储等说明
compare jump and many more flow this way
以这种方式比较跳转和更多流
and the actual data being processed flows this way
被处理的实际数据是这样流动的
and then over here
然后在这里
are the blocks that actually execute the arithmetic
是实际执行算术的块
branching and storing of data
数据的分支和存储
let's move on to a few additional details
让我们继续一些额外的细节
about this processor
关于这个处理器
all smartphones use a reduced instruction set computer
所有智能手机都使用精简指令集计算机
or risk architecture
或风险架构
and almost all of these architectures are licensed from
几乎所有这些架构都从
a company called arm
一家名为arm的公司
which stands for Advanced Risk Machines
代表高级风险机器
some companies like apple
一些像苹果这样的公司
license the instruction set architecture
授权指令集架构
or ISA
或ISA
from arm
从手臂
and use this ISA to design their processor cores
并使用此ISA来设计他们的处理器内核
in house whereas other companies like Qualcomm
在内部，而高通等其他公司
license complete blueprints
许可完整蓝图
which are technically called intellectual property
技术上称为知识产权
cores from arm
臂芯
Qualcomm then integrates the arm IP cores into its Socs
高通然后将arm IP内核集成到其SOC中
sometimes keeping the design of the core as is
有时保持核心的设计原样
but more often modifying or customizing the arm core
但更常见的是修改或定制臂芯
to better suit Qualcomm's design needs
更好地满足高通的设计需求
and in the process
在这个过程中
Qualcomm rebrands the name of the CPU
高通重新命名CPU
however
然而
all this information still begs the question of
所有这些信息仍然回避了一个问题
how do these Socs get designed and manufactured
这些SOC是如何设计和制造的？
instead of talking about the entire design process
而不是谈论整个设计过程
which you can find in the creator's comments
你可以在创作者的评论中找到。
we're going to discuss two design principles of the Soc
我们将讨论Soc的两个设计原则
the first principle is called hardware acceleration
第一个原则叫做硬件加速
and this principle deals with the fact that
这个原则涉及这样一个事实
instead of having a single
而不是有一个
very powerful general purpose CPU
非常强大的通用CPU
with a lot of cores
有很多核心
this chip has a variety of special purpose blocks
该芯片具有各种特殊用途块
dedicated to performing specific functions
致力于执行特定功能
these special function blocks or hardware accelerators
这些特殊功能块或硬件加速器
compute their tasks faster
更快地计算他们的任务
while using significantly less power than
同时使用的功率明显低于
if the same operation were performed by
如果由执行相同的操作
the general purpose CPU
通用CPU
for example as we saw with
例如，正如我们看到的那样
the process is involved in taking a picture
该过程涉及拍照
there is an entire block of the Soc
Soc有一整块
that's dedicated to processing the image
专门用于处理图像
and then a separate block whose job is to encode
然后是一个单独的块，其工作是编码
decode or compress or decompress the image
解码或压缩或解压缩图像
and if you're watching this video on your smartphone
如果你在智能手机上看这段视频
it's actively decompressing this video as you watch it
当你看的时候，它会主动解压这个视频。
these sections are useful for taking pictures
这些部分对拍照很有用
but critical for recording 4k video
但对录制4k视频至关重要
and saving battery life
并节省电池寿命
hardware accelerators are utilized
使用硬件加速器
for pretty much all computationally
几乎所有的计算
intensive tasks
密集任务
performed by your smartphone
由您的智能手机执行
the next design principle is that
下一个设计原则是
because Socs are used in smartphones
因为Socs用于智能手机
which operate on a battery
依靠电池运行
there's a huge focus on having the Soc
人们非常关注拥有Soc
consume as little power as possible
尽可能少地消耗电力
one example of low power consumption design
低功耗设计的一个例子
is in the CPU
在CPU中
instead of having all high performance cores
而不是拥有所有高性能内核
chip designers often follow a big
芯片设计师经常遵循一个大的
little design structure
小设计结构
where there are two or four big cores
那里有两到四个大核心
that are high performance cores
是高性能内核
but consume more power
但消耗更多的电力
and four little cores that are lower performance
和四个性能较低的小内核
but are energy efficient
但节能吗？
and your smartphone prioritizes using these
您的智能手机优先使用这些
lower performance
低绩效
energy efficient cores
节能核心
when possible
在可能的情况下
furthermore the design of the transistor
此外，晶体管的设计
which is the smallest
哪个是最小的
and fundamental building block of the Soc
和Soc的基本组成部分
has had its design evolved to both be smaller
它的设计已经进化到两者都更小
but more importantly to consume less power
但更重要的是消耗更少的电力
as of 2020 the
截至2020年
latest technology of transistors is called a gate
晶体管的最新技术被称为栅极
all around field effect transistor
环绕场效应晶体管
let's finally
让我们最终
move on to how these chips are manufactured
继续讨论这些芯片是如何制造的
to start the lion's share of all Socs
开始所有Socs的最大份额
get manufactured by a single company
由一家公司制造
called TSMC
叫台积电
or Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company
或者台湾半导体制造公司
and a smaller yet increasing proportion of Socs
Socs的比例越来越小
are manufactured by Samsung
由三星制造
these microchips are manufactured on 300
这些微芯片是300制造的
millimeter wide silicon wafers
毫米宽硅片
in factories called FAB's
在一个叫FAB的工厂里
in order to manufacture an array of chips
为了制造芯片阵列
the silicon wafer has to go through a series of 120
硅片必须通过一系列120
to 160 processes
到160个进程
or steps performed by dozens of different machines
或由数十台不同机器执行的步骤
this is the most common sequence of steps
这是最常见的步骤顺序
for manufacturing microchips
用于制造微芯片
as you see there are only a dozen or so steps
如你所见，只有十几个台阶。
but each of these processes
但这些过程中的每一个
are performed dozens of times
被执行了几十次
in order to build an incredibly complex layout of
为了建立一个令人难以置信的复杂布局
transistors
晶体管
but this video is getting too long
但是这个视频太长了。
so we'll have to save the details of each step
所以我们必须保存每一步的细节
for a future video
对于未来的视频
for now
暂时
here's what a nanoscopic view of the Soc looks like
这是Soc的纳米视图
on the bottom is the silicon wafer
底部是硅片
and the billions of transistors are implanted
数十亿个晶体管被植入
and built into
并内置于
and on top of the silicon
在硅的顶部
on top of the layer of transistors
在晶体管层之上
are layers of local interconnects
是本地互连的层
that connect transistors to one another
将晶体管相互连接
and then on top of that
然后最重要的是
are the global interconnects
是全球互联
that connect sections of transistors
连接晶体管的部分
this is just a small fraction of the entire Soc layout
这只是整个Soc布局的一小部分
let's zoom out
让我们缩小
in order to get a sense of the size of these components
为了了解这些组件的大小
I'm sure you've heard
你肯定听说了
the transistors are incredibly small
晶体管非常小
and well here's a single grain of fine table salt
这里有一粒细食盐
mind blowing right
令人兴奋的权利
it makes you think
它让你思考
the potential of humanity
人类的潜力
to reach incredible levels of science and engineering
达到令人难以置信的科学和工程水平
is limitless
是无限的